GABBY BANIQUED

+301 751 7970 · ollergabrielle@gmail.com · gabbley.github.io Fort Washington, MD

COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHER, PRODUCT DESIGNER

I am a Computer Science Teacher at a Catholic high school with 10+ years experience working with various Catholic ministries that each focus on ministering to specific age groups or communities. My passion is developing digital products that support ministries in their work to evangelize and provide spiritual nourishment. I am well-versed in working in a fast-paced environment with limited resources, and embrace such challenges in the service of an important mission.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BISHOP IRETON HIGH SCHOOL - Alexandria, VA Computer Science Teacher

Aug 2023 - Present

- Teach AP (Advanced Placement) Computer Science A, Honors Advanced Programming (Java), Web Design (HTML/CSS, Figma). Develop lessons with a high degree of education customization based on student performance, behavior, learning styles, special needs.
- Co-lead a Collaborative Learning Team (CLT) consisting of 11 teachers across 8 departments
 focused on Al-usage for teachers. During meetings, we conduct workshops for teachers to use
 common chatbots (ChatGPT, Copilot) in lesson planning as well as discuss strategies to facilitate
 appropriate use of Al in the classrooms.

Lead Hackathon Organizer

- Plan an annual Hackathon "Hack BI", a student-led event consisting of a keynote session, instructional programming workshops, career panels, and two separate competitions for high school and middle school participants.
- Oversee and teach student leaders how to organize an event with 200+ attendees.

Success, Research and Development Teams to drive informed decision-making.

Diversity Initiatives Assistant

Develop and execute campaigns to provide representation and education to the school community.
 Such campaigns include social media posts, educational content to display throughout the school building, school-wide activities, and an annual Culture Fair, a school-wide event for students and faculty to celebrate and share their different cultures and backgrounds.

MENTOR COLLECTIVE - Boston, MA (Remote) Data Analyst Intern

Jun 2021 - May 2022

- Built live, custom reporting dashboards based on stakeholder requirements to determine effective business practices. Brought actionable and meaningful data insights to Product, Sales, Customer
- Processed time-critical support requests from end users to pull custom data sets in support of dayto-day business functions of the Product, Research, Program Success, and Marketing teams. Used PostgreSQL to guery from large datasets commingled with legacy data and structures.
- Hosted a technical workshop to demo and teach non-technical employees how to use Metabase, our data visualization tool. Created materials, documentation, modified queries, and updated visualizations to be more user-friendly for non-technical users. Answered questions and hosted an open discussion.

RECENT PROJECTS

ask me things | Question Decks for Meaningful Connection

Dec 2024 - Present

- Developed a functional version of ask-me-things using HTML, CSS, and Javascript, focusing only on functionality. Based on this simple version, created low-fidelity prototypes on paper to experiment with different layouts and flow.
- Currently creating the first iteration of UI mockups in Figma.

musicmin.app | Instant Worship Slides and Chords

Dec 2022 - Mar 2023

- Designed database schema to support updated data collection goals. Created relational database and UI mockups in Figma for its 2.0 release, incorporating new features. Presented mockups to the development team and made iterative improvements based on feedback.
- Conducted a UI/UX evaluation using Nielsen's Usability Heuristics, prioritized issues by severity, and presented written recommendations to the development team.

Data Science Pipeline Project | Workplace Attitudes Towards Mental Health and their Impact on Employee Productivity

Apr 2021 - May 2021

- Collected, transformed, analyzed, and visualized survey data from Open Sourcing Mental Illness
 using Pandas, Matplotlib, and SciKit-Learn. Made predictive analyses regarding the relationship
 between workplace attitudes and productivity using a logistic regression model.
- Skills demonstrated: Python, Data scraping, Data cleaning, Handling missing data, Exploratory Data analysis, Predictive modeling, Trend analysis, Pandas, NumPy, SciKi-Learn, and Jupyter/IPython Notebook.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND COLLEGE PARK, College Park, MD Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2018-May 2022

With a Concentration in Data Science and a Minor in Sustainability Studies

TRINITY WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY, Online

Continuing Education Classroom Management Foundations and Philosophy of Education

Nov 2023, Jul 2024

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Application Mockup Tools: Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Canva
- Languages: Proficient in Java, Python, SQL, HTML/CSS, Javascript; Experience with Ruby, R, C++, C
- **Data Tools:** Pandas, NumPy, SciKit, Matlab, Metabase, Advanced Microsoft Excel (VBA, Pivot tables, V-lookup, data validation, charting, visualization)
- Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite, MySQL
- Software and Applications: Visual Studio Code, Docker, VMWare, Android Studio, Jupyter Notebook, Git, Github, Microsoft Office, Google Suite, Asana, Notion, Slack, Zoom
- Other Technical Skills: UX/UI Design, Agile Software Development, Linux/Unix Scripting